

BROOKE KUMAR

PROJECT MANAGER | WEB DEVELOPER

m: (651) 399-3097 | mrsbrookekumar@gmail.com | Minneapolis, MN

PROFILE

Experienced Program Manager successful at cross-functional collaboration and project execution.

Specializing in empowering others through dedicated consistency and delivery with an emphasis on buy-in and trust building. Self-motivated professional with proven results and excited about career growth.

HIGHLIGHTED SKILLS

- Microsoft Suite
- PMP (Microsoft)
- Report analysis
- · Project planning
- Advanced MS Project
- Gap assessment
- Presenting to large groups (50+)
- Advanced data visualization
- Spotfire
- Web Development (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API integration, Node, Express.JS, MySQL)
- Stakeholder success
- Cross-functional collaboration
- Project monitoring and execution
- Socialization of concepts though presentations, conversations, and networking
- · Consultation and knowledge sharing

CERTFICATIONS

- Intermediate Excel, Microsoft 2016
- PMP (anticipated January 2020)
- Full Stack Coding (anticipated March 2020)

FOLLOW ME

GitHub: brookekumar.github.io **LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/brooke-kumar

BROOKE KUMAR PROJECT MANAGER · WEB DEVELOPER

WORK HISTORY

PD Program Management Specialist

MEDTRONIC

DECEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

- Work with functional groups to advocate for alignment across projects within a \$25M/year remediation portfolio
- Lead project completion efforts across all functional groups
- -Create tools to drive consistency and reporting for extended team members and executives
- Create training and education tools for enterprise excellence
- Fulfill all project management business requirements; report to stakeholders and leadership monthly

Business Analyst

ABBOTT

APRIL 2017 - DECEMBER 2017

Regulatory Affairs Specialist

DAVITA CLINICAL RESEARCH FEBRUARY 2016 - FEBRUARY 2017

I have a passion for leveraging Program Management fundamentals to lead functional teams to success from planning to execution. I also have experience implementing tools to execute projects within a portfolio.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota

CONTINUING STUDIES, MINNEAPOLIS, MN
CERTIFICATE, FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

Carthage College

COLLEGE OF LIBERAL ARTS, KENOSHA, WI BA IN RELIGIOUS STUDIES, CLASS OF 2014

- cum laude
- Outstanding thesis, Humanities department
- Outstanding thesis, Religious Studies department; honors